（微妙的爆炸）
(subtle blast)
- 管道函数内部发生了什么？
- What happens inside the pipeline function?
在这段视频中，我们将看看实际发生了什么
In this video, we will look at what actually happens
当我们使用 Transformers 库的
when we use the pipeline function
pipeline 函数时
of the Transformers library.
更具体地说，我们将看看
More specifically, we will look at
情绪分析管道，
the sentiment analysis pipeline,
以及它是如何从以下两个句子中得出的
and how it went from the two following sentences
正负标签
to the positive and negative labels
加上各自的分数。
with their respective scores.
正如我们在管道视频中看到的那样，
As we have seen in the pipeline video,
管道分为三个阶段。
there are three stages in the pipeline.
首先，我们将原始文本转换为数字
First, we convert the raw texts to numbers
该模型可以使用分词器来理解。
the model can make sense of, using a tokenizer.
然后，这些数字通过模型，
Then, those numbers go through the model,
输出逻辑。
which outputs logits.
最后是后处理步骤
Finally, the post-processing steps
将这些 logits 转换为标签和分数。
transforms those logits into labels and score.
让我们详细看看这三个步骤，
Let's look in detail at those three steps,
以及如何使用 Transformers 库复制它们，
and how to replicate them using the Transformers library,
从第一阶段开始，标记化。
beginning with the first stage, tokenization.
令牌化过程有几个步骤。
The tokenization process has several steps.
首先，文本被分成称为标记的小块。
First, the text is split into small chunks called token.
它们可以是单词、单词的一部分或标点符号。
They can be words, parts of words or punctuation symbols.
然后 tokenizer 将有一些特殊的标记
Then the tokenizer will had some special tokens
如果模型期望它们。
if the model expect them.
在这里，所使用的模型在开头需要一个 CLS 令牌
Here, the model used expects a CLS token at the beginning
以及用于分类的句子末尾的 SEP 标记。
and a SEP token at the end of the sentence to classify.
最后，标记器将每个标记与其唯一 ID 匹配
Lastly, the tokenizer matches each token to its unique ID
在预训练模型的词汇表中。
in the vocabulary of the pretrained model.
要加载这样的分词器，
To load such a tokenizer,
Transformers 库提供了 AutoTokenizer API。
the Transformers library provides the AutoTokenizer API.
这个类最重要的方法是 from_pretrained，
The most important method of this class is from_pretrained,
这将下载并缓存配置
which will download and cache the configuration
以及与给定检查点相关联的词汇表。
and the vocabulary associated to a given checkpoint.
这里默认使用的 checkpoint
Here, the checkpoint used by default
用于情绪分析管道
for the sentiment analysis pipeline
是 distilbert base uncased finetuned sst2 英语，
is distilbert base uncased finetuned sst2 English,
这有点含糊。
which is a bit of a mouthful.
我们实例化一个与该检查点关联的分词器，
We instantiate a tokenizer associated with that checkpoint,
然后给它输入两个句子。
then feed it the two sentences.
由于这两个句子的大小不同，
Since those two sentences are not of the same size,
我们需要填充最短的一个
we will need to pad the shortest one
能够构建一个数组。
to be able to build an array.
这是由分词器完成的
This is done by the tokenizer
使用选项 padding=True。
with the option padding=True.
使用 truncation=True，我们确保任何句子更长
With truncation=True, we ensure that any sentence longer
比模型可以处理的最大值被截断。
than the maximum the model can handle is truncated.
最后，return_tensors 选项告诉分词器
Lastly, the return_tensors option tells the tokenizer
返回 PyTorch 张量。
to return a PyTorch tensor.
看看结果，
Looking at the result,
我们看到我们有一个有两个键的字典。
we see we have a dictionary with two keys.
输入 ID 包含两个句子的 ID，
Input IDs contains the IDs of both sentences,
在应用填充的地方使用零。
with zeros where the padding is applied.
第二把钥匙，注意面具，
The second key, attention mask,
指示已应用填充的位置，
indicates where padding has been applied,
所以模型不会关注它。
so the model does not pay attention to it.
这就是标记化步骤中的全部内容。
This is all what is inside the tokenization step.
现在让我们来看看第二步，模型。
Now let's have a look at the second step, the model.
至于分词器，有一个 AutoModel API，
As for the tokenizer, there is an AutoModel API,
使用 from_pretrained 方法。
with a from_pretrained method.
它将下载并缓存模型的配置
It will download and cache the configuration of the model
以及预训练的权重。
as well as the pretrained weights.
但是，AutoModel API 只会实例化
However, the AutoModel API will only instantiate
模特的身体，
the body of the model,
也就是说，模型中剩下的部分
that is, the part of the model that is left
一旦预训练头被移除。
once the pretraining head is removed.
它会输出一个高维张量
It will output a high-dimensional tensor
这是通过的句子的表示，
that is a representation of the sentences passed,
但这不是直接有用的
but which is not directly useful
对于我们的分类问题。
for our classification problem.
这里张量有两个句子，
Here the tensor has two sentences,
每十六个令牌，
each of sixteen token,
最后一个维度是我们模型的隐藏大小，768。
and the last dimension is the hidden size of our model, 768.
要获得与我们的分类问题相关的输出，
To get an output linked to our classification problem,
我们需要使用 AutoModelForSequenceClassification 类。
we need to use the AutoModelForSequenceClassification class.
它与 AutoModel 类完全一样工作，
It works exactly as the AutoModel class,
除了它会建立一个模型
except that it will build a model
带分类头。
with a classification head.
每个常见的 NLP 任务在 Transformers 库
There is one auto class for each common NLP task
都有一个自动类
in the Transformers library.
在这里，在给我们的模型两个句子之后，
Here, after giving our model the two sentences,
我们得到一个大小为二乘二的张量；
we get a tensor of size two by two;
每个句子和每个可能的标签都有一个结果。
one result for each sentence and for each possible label.
这些输出还不是概率。
Those outputs are not probabilities yet.
我们可以看到它们的总和不为 1。
We can see they don't sum to 1.
这是因为 Transformers 库的每个模型
This is because each model of the Transformers library
返回逻辑。
returns logits.
为了理解这些逻辑，
To make sense of those logits,
我们需要深入研究第三个
we need to dig into the third
管道的最后一步，后处理。
and last step of the pipeline, post-processing.
要将 logits 转换为概率，
To convert logits into probabilities,
我们需要对它们应用一个 SoftMax 层。
we need to apply a SoftMax layer to them.
正如我们所见，这会将它们转换为正数
As we can see, this transforms them into positive numbers
总和为 1。
that sum up to 1.
最后一步是知道哪些对应
The last step is to know which of those corresponds
正面或负面的标签。
to the positive or the negative label.
这是由模型配置的 id2label 字段给出的。
This is given by the id2label field of the model config.
第一概率，索引 0，
The first probabilities, index 0,
对应负标签，
correspond to the negative label,
秒，索引 1，对应于正标签。
and the seconds, index 1, correspond to the positive label.
这就是我们的分类器的构建方式
This is how our classifier built
使用管道功能选择了那些标签
with the pipeline function picked those labels
并计算出这些分数。
and computed those scores.
既然你知道每个步骤是如何工作的，
Now that you know how each steps works,
你可以轻松地根据需要调整它们。
you can easily tweak them to your needs.
（微妙的爆炸）
(subtle blast)